一边去。
Move aside.
我们正在寻找那个女孩。
We are looking for the girl.
那个德国人在哪里？
Where is the german?
你正在寻找的那个人，
The one you're searching for, she
她两天前回到吕贝克了。
returned to Lubec two days ago.
你是施莱格尔太太？
You are Frau Schlegel?
她是你的孩子吗？
She is your child?
是的，但她不住在这里。
Yes, but she doesn't live here.
她在吕贝克和她阿姨一起住。
She lives with her aunt in Lubec.
你搞错了。
You're making a mistake.
像你这样的女人，只会污染。
Women like you, you contaminate.
如果她跟她母亲那怕有一点相似，她也会欣然接受
If she's anything like her mother, she'll be open also--
从里到外的肮脏
to contaminate from within.
你找不到她的。
You won't find her.
因为她不住在这里。
Because she doesn't live here.
来，蕾娜，他们走了。
Leyna, come They've gone.
1944年春。
Spring 1944.
那一年我满十六岁。
That was the year I turned 16.
像我这样来自莱茵兰的孩子
Children like me from the Rhineland
被称为莱茵兰的杂种或“希特勒的麻烦”
were known as Rhineland bastards or "Hitler's problem,"
因为即便我的父亲是非洲人
because our German nationality automatically
而且不在身边，我们依旧能够从白人母亲
came through our white mothers even though our fathers
那边获得德国国籍。
were African and often absent.
我的同类人数稀少，以致在我过去16年里
There were so few of us that in my entire 16 years,
从来没有见过另外一个和我一样的人。
I never saw another soul like me.
生日快乐，可爱的女孩。
Happy Birthday, sweet girl.
谢谢你，海因里希太太。
Thank you, Frau Heinrich.
希特勒想秘密地处决我们，
Hitler
wanted to deal with us secretly,
避免被德国群众视作对我们雅利安人母亲的攻击。
without being seen by Germany to be attacking our Aryan mothers.
所以我们拥有犹太人没有的自由，
So though we had a freedom that the Jews did not have,
但我们还是得掩掩藏藏，尤其是
still we had to be guarded, especially
当盖世太保密探来吕德斯海姆看我们的时候。
once the Gestapo started to visit us in Rudesheim.
并不是说我不知道自己不一样。
It wasn't that I had not known I was different.
而是在我16岁的时候，我才真正体会到。
It was that as I reached 16, I really began to feel it.
正是那一年，我意识到了希特勒对我们这群人有着一个计划。
That was the year I realized Hitler had a plan for us.
我们为什么去柏林？
Why are we going to Berlin?
去消失。
To be invisible.
科恩，别说了。
Stop talking, Koen.
看你的书去。
Read your book.
我有我的画画本，但我没有铅笔。
I have my drawing book, but no pencil.
没铅笔我画不了。
I can't draw without one.
你想要根铅笔？
You want a pencil?
我想我也许能够帮你，小伙子。
I think that I might be able to help you, little man.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
他就是事儿多。
He's restless.
他是个男孩子。
He's a boy.
我们长大了也不会变的。
We never grow out of it.
你的文件呢？
Your papers?
是，当然。
Yes, of course.
我带了我们所有的文件。
I have all of our papers.
给你。
Here.
施莱格尔？
Schlegel?
是。
Yes.
不要找事。
Invisible.
这里不像莱茵兰。
Here is not like the Rhineland.
他们不会因为你这样的孩子感到不安
They're not bothered with children like you
也不会嚷着要“修理”你。
or this talk of fixing you.
生活会好起来的。
Life will be good again.
我保证。
I promise.
今天，有个新来的女孩会加入我们。
We have a new girl joining us today.
她的名字是蕾娜・施莱格尔。
Her name is Leyna Schlegel.
起立。
Stand up.
施莱格尔是个不错的德国名字，但你的脸，如此的不像德国人。
Schlegel is a good German name, but your face, so un-German.
请告诉我，蕾娜的五官
Leyna has facial features in common
和哪个洲的人相似呢？
with people of which continent?
格蕾塔。
Greta.
非洲。
Africa.
正确，所以你这样的女孩是怎么
Indeed So how does a girl like you
拥有像施莱格尔这样德式的名字呢？
come to have a name so Germanic as Schlegel?
施莱格尔是我母亲的名字。
Schlegel is my mother's name.
那你父亲的名字呢？
And what is your father's name?
你什么时候告诉我关于我父亲的事？
When will you tell me about my father?
他从头到脚都是黑色皮肤。
He was black from head to toe.
我想知道他是谁。
I want to know who he was.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
你什么都知道。
You know everything.
当时，我只比你大一点。
I was just a little older than you.
犯了一些错误。
Made mistakes.
错误？
Mistakes?
不是说你。
Not you.
科恩，请给我倒点水。
Koen, get me some water, please.
他是个很出色的士兵。
He was a good soldier.
但这些我都告诉过你了。
But I've told you all this.
我不知道还有什么好说的。
I don't know what else.
你们为什么没有结婚？
Why did you not marry?
穆勒先生昨天批评了我，因为他告诉我
Mr. Mueller slapped me yesterday, because he told me
你即拥有最优等的白人血统
that you were the first of all people who are white
又有最低等的黑人血统。
and the worse of all people, black.
也就是黑白混血儿。
That's what a Mulatto is.
但我告诉他那不是真的。
But I told him that's not true.
对我来说，你是最好的。
To me you are the best of everything.
你的头发脏了。
Your hair is dirty.
我今晚给你洗。
I'll wash it for you tonight.
希特勒万岁。
Heil Hitler.
嘿，你不该跟他们一起吗，你个猴子？
Hey, shouldn't you be going with them, monkey?
威廉刚从维也纳回来。
Wilhelm just returned from Vienna.
但他知道我们要来吗？
But he knows we're coming?
对，当然。
Yes, of course.
我告诉他了。
I told him.
她真的很漂亮。
She actually is beautiful.
和她父亲一个模子刻出来的。
And he looks just like Father.
来啊，蕾娜。
Go on, Leyna.
坐下。
Sit down.
我没想到你会和孩子一起来。
I didn't expect you with the children.
今天他们在门口看见了一个黑人。
Today they saw a Negro at the door.
第二天就会遭受犹太人的待遇，你懂吗？
Tomorrow it will be a Jew, you know?
没人看见我们，希达。
Nobody saw us, Hida.
蕾娜，你先走。
Leyna, go ahead of me.
看看能不能在店铺关门之前
See if you can pick up a good loaf of bread
拿到一块不错的面包。
before the store closes.
你把科恩带上。
Take Koen with you.
蕾娜，求你了，走后面的门。
Leyna, please, use the back.
柯思婷，我想让你理解，
Kerstin, I want you to understand,
我跟你家无冤无仇。
I have nothing against your family.
而如果要在你的孩子和我们之间作出选择，我知道，
And a choice between your child and us, well, I know,
这根本没有选择。
it's no choice at all.
即便我为德皇杀过人。
But I spilled blood for the Kaiser.
上个月他们仍把我生病的父亲关了两个晚上
And last month they kept my sick father over two nights
就因为有人让他们相信我父亲的妈妈是个犹太人。
because someone convinced them he had a Jewish mother.
而现在，你带着你的黑人过来。
And now you bring your Negro here.
没有任何顾虑把我们都置于危险之中。
You compromised me, us, your sister, without any regard.
威廉。
Wilhelm.
请你听我说完，我发誓之后我们再也不会来打扰你们了。
Listen for just a moment and you
will never hear from us again.
我需要文件。
I need papers.
柯思婷。
Kerstin.
能证明蕾娜不能生育的文件。
Something to say Leyna has been sterilized.
你真够特别的啊。
You really are quite unique.
威廉，你有能力做到的。
Wilhelm, you have access.
一份证明她身体被改变了的盖世太保文件。
A Gestapo document declaring her physically changed.
你能做到的。
You can do this.
我知道你可以。
I know you can.
你该走了，柯思婷。
You should leave, Kerstin.
希达，求你了。
Hida, please.
我没想到命令会影响到柏林。
I didn't think the order would extend to Berlin.
我本希望她在这里能够获得安全。
I hoped she would be safe here.
但两天前他们来了。
But two days ago they came.
她出去了。
She was out.
我告诉了他们文件在她身上，但我害怕。
I told them she carries the papers with her but I'm afraid.
我怕他们会从街上把她带走
I'm afraid that they will take her from the streets,
从学校，任何我保护不了她的地方。
from the school, anywhere that I can't protect her.
蕾娜，我们走吧。
Leyna, let's go.
你为什么让她上学？
Why did you put her in school?
你什么毛病？
What's the matter with you?
我不能把她藏起来。
I can't hide her.
如果不是学校，就得是干苦工去。
If not school, then labor service.
谁知道会发生什么呢？
Who knows where she would end?
每个女孩都要去做苦工。
All the girls must do labor service.
她也一样。
She's no different.
你想让她享有特权吗？
You want her to be special?
不。
No.
我想让她和别人一样。
I want her to be like everyone else.
不被贴上标签。
Unremarkable.
那么她就得直面这场无法逃离的战争。
Then she will not escape this war as if it never happened.
我们谁都无法逃离，柯思婷。
None of us will
manage that, Kerstin.
甘特。
Gunter.
哪里？
Where?
那声音是从哪里来的？
Where did that voice come from?
啊。
Ah.
来点面包，甘特，谢谢。
Some bread, please, Gunter.
你怎么样？
How are you?
不错？
Good?
正在安顿下来？
Settling in?
我想家。
I miss home.
早啊。
Morning.
啊，我想，那是个笑容吧。
Ah, is that a, yes, I think a smile.
好点了。
That's better.
还有人在等。
There are people waiting.
我总是在后面存着一块好的，但给你了。
I always keep good come back, but you can have it.
现在你听我说
Now listen to me.
如果你姐姐忘了要笑，
If your sister forgets to smile, you
你得让她想起甘特的脸。
remind her of Gunter's face.
很搞笑，是不是？
It's funny, yes?
是。
Yes.
我现在能走了吗？
Can I go now?
嗯，你可以跟其他男孩子一起走了。
Yes, you can go with the other boys.
去吧。
Go on then.
科恩。
Koen.
我没有选择。
I have no choice.
法律说你必须得走。
The law says you must go.
但在你要去的那个地方，他们会教你很多东西。
But where you are going, they will teach you many things.
很多都是有道理，感觉是对的，
Lots will make sense and feel right,
但很多会让你感到疑惑
but so much will be confusing because it
因为它和你在家里学到的东西不同。
will be different to the things you learn here at home.
但我希望你理解，没有人
But I want you to understand that nobody
能比一个母亲更了解自己的儿子，
can know a son better than a mother,
任何老师，任何队长都不行。
no teacher, no group leader.
我希望，科恩，你选择永远不忘记这个，
I hope, Koen, that you choose never to forget this,
你把我教你的放在这里和这里。
that you keep what I teach you in here and here.
科恩，你理解我说的吗？
Do you understand me, Koen?
蕾娜！
Leyna!
我没有看到你。
I didn't see you.
蕾娜？
Leyna?
对不起。
Sorry.
让我看看你。
Let me look at you.
你应该更小心一点。
You should be more careful.
我需要你把你带回家，好清理这些伤口。
I need to get you home so we can clean these wounds.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你为什么这么早跑到楼里？
Why are you in the building so early?
队长们在男孩子们到达之前有个会议要开。
The leaders in meeting before the boys arrive.
我跟他们说这是必须的。
I told them we need to.
你在给自己找麻烦吗？
Are you making problems for yourself?
年龄大的那些还在抢别人的零花钱。
The older ones are taking pocket money from the others.
昨天还有孩子的母亲冲我耳朵里瞎喊。
Yesterday I had mothers screaming in my ears.
等等！
Wait!
问我要。
Ask.
嗯。
Hm.
别伸手就拿。
Don't take.
我们有点晚了，纳格尔太太。
We're a little late, Frau Nagel.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
一个小疯子骑着自行车把她撞倒了。
A little hooligan ran her over with his bike.
是个意外。
It was an accident.
你该说什么，科恩？
What do you say, Koen?
谢谢你，纳格尔太太。
Thank you, Frau Nagel.
下回下国际象棋，我要让你输得屁滚尿流，对吧？
And next time, I kick your ass at chess, huh?
一位先生让我替你拿着。
A gentleman asked me to take it for you.
你不在的时候，他站在你的门口外面了。
He was at your door while you were gone.
我问了他的名字，但他不愿意告诉我。
I ask him his name, but he didn't want to tell me.
是威廉。
Wilhelm.
希达不能知道这件事。
Hida must never know.
这里，拿着这些。
Here, take them.
一套医生的文件也填好了。
A set of the doctor's papers has also been filed.
谁？
Who?
鲁德谢姆市的一个眼目，
A connection in the municipality of Rudesheim,
制度下的一个关键人物。
one who is critical
of the regime.
一个共产党？
A communist?
你有共产党联系人？
You have communist contacts?
这里面有很多
There are more papers inside that
需要在鲁德谢姆存档的文件。
must be archived in Rudesheim.
把他们签好字，按要求还给我。
Have them signed and returned to me as instructed.
这之后，你就得与你的妹妹断绝来往。
And then you must forget that you ever had a sister.
给。
Here.
什么？
What?
没什么。
Nothing.
你擦鞋跟你哈里叔叔似的
You polish like your Uncle Harry--
像个女孩一样。
like a girl.
哦好吧，反正哈里叔叔告诉我，我擦鞋跟你似的。
Oh, well Uncle Harry told me I polish like you.
你弄完了的话，去把你自己清理干净。
When you're finished, go and get yourself cleaned up.
你头发里有泥巴。
You have mud in your hair.
我今天瞄靶棒极了。
My targets were excellent today.
我得去汉堡，但周日，
I have to go to Hamburg tonight but Sunday,
星期天我们去捕些鱼，如何？
Sunday we'll catch some fish, yes?
我有文件要给你。
I have papers for you.
你去哪都要戴着它们。
You should carry them with you wherever you go.
它们会保护你。
They will protect you.
你从哪 -
Where did you--
它们是假的，但足够了。
They're false, but they're enough.
没有人会知道的。
No one will know.
威廉需要你把这些也签好。
Wilhelm needs you to sign these also.
等我把这些寄回给他，
If I send them back to him, he will
他会保证我们以后不再被打扰。
make sure it's in the right place for us to be left alone.
这是什么？
What is it?
一个你不会犯下罪过
A declaration that you will not
将自己的种族与如何有德国血液的人
commit the crime of racial mixing
混为一体的声明。
with anyone of German blood.
我是个德国人。
I am of German blood.
签字只是为了让他们不要来打扰我们。
It's just a signature to keep them away.
没有任何意义的。
It means nothing.
一定有意义，不然我为什么要签？
It means something surely or why should I sign?
我不签。
I won't.
好吧。
Fine.
那他们就会来抓你，蕾娜，
Then they will come for you, Leyna,
然后他们会逼着你签，到时候就不是又假又空的文件。
and they will make you sign, not false, empty papers.
而是真的文件，而在此之前，他们会真的修理你
Real ones, and not before they have fixed you in reality
在你体内动刀子。
and cut your insides to do so.
不论是你还是你弟弟
Neither you nor your brother entered
都是经历了痛苦才来到世上。
this world without pain.
但如果没有你们两个，我不会有我的这一生。
But I could not be in this life without you both.
某一天，你也应该知道
You should also know the blessing
作为母亲的恩赐，蕾娜。
of motherhood one day, Leyna.
我想让你体会到。
I want that for you.
如果你不签，他们会对你
If you do not sign, they will do to you
做一些不可能挽回的事情。
what can never be undone.
你会成为他们改造的产物。
You will be who they have made you.
那个允许波兰拿走帝国的这一片土地
What was the treaty that enabled Poland to take
的条约是什么？
this land from the empire?
安娜？
Anna?
凡尔赛条约。
Versailles.
施莱格尔。
Schlegel.
签署这条条约的五位重要领导人是谁？
The five principle leaders were signatories to this treaty?
希特勒万岁。
Heil Hitler.
坐下。
Sit.
施莱格尔，站起来。
Schlegel, stand.
过来。
Come.
把书放下。
Leave your books.
你不会再需要它们了。
You won't need them anymore.
拿着你的包。
And take your bag.
他们没有伤害你。
They didn't hurt you.
这是唯一要紧的事。
That's all that matters.
他们可以不让你上学，但他们
They can force you from school, but they
不能阻止你学习。
can't stop you learning.
你在家里学习。
You'll learn here at home.
但你现在会被召去劳动了。
But you will be conscripted to work now.
我为你今天的劳动感到骄傲。
I was proud of how you worked today.
你的成长如此之快。
You're growing so quickly.
我有件现在对你来说很合身的外套。
I have a coat that will fit you nicely now.
开车送我们回家？
Drive us home?
不了，谢谢。
No, thank you.
我…我骑车。
I-- I'll cycle.
哦，请。
Oh, please.
你跟着我们回家了。
You followed us home.
我想知道你是不是没事。
I wanted to know if you're all right.
我没是。
I am.
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
我不知道，你的瘀青吧。
I don't know, your bruise.
再见了。
I'll see you.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
甘特
Gunter,..
甘特！
Gunter!
脱下来。
Take them off.
脱掉！
Off!
他们没把你的包皮切干净啊，犹太人。
They didn't circumcise you good enough, Jew.
我能把它修好。
I can fix that.
发生什么了？
What happened?
他是个犹太人？
He was a Jew?
打印海报。
Printing leaflets.
他跟其他学生一起密谋着什么。
He was plotting with other students.
把十字架跟个徽章似的戴着。
He wore a crucifix like it was a badge.
跟些腐臭的犹太复国运动组织混在一起。
Running with some rotten Zionist group.
我在甘特的店铺外面听到有人讨论。
I heard some people outside Gunter's store.
甘特今天遭遇了一些事。
Something happened to him today.
我知道。
I know.
我在现场。
I was there.
我看见了。
I saw it.
他当时在弄他的面包。
He was touching the bread.
但他是犹太人。
But he was Jewish.
科恩，别傻了。
Don't be stupid, Koen.
他是个好犹太人。
He was good Jew.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
好犹太人？
Good Jew?
他是个活生生的人。
He was a human being.
如果我禁止你和我走在同一条街上
If I forbade you from sharing the streets with me
只因为你的脸上有雀斑，我的言语有能力
because your face is freckled, should my words make
让你失去作为人的资格吗？
you any less of a human being?
这样的话是不是任何人都应该
Should that mean that anyone should shoot
在大街上把你像一条狗一样打死？
you in the street like a dog?
对不起。
I'm sorry.
你看到这样一件事，我很抱歉，蕾娜。
I'm sorry you had to see such a thing, Leyna.
对你也如此，科恩。
Also to you, Koen.
这不是你的错误，这是我的责任
It's not your fault. It's my job to protect
来规范你听到的东西，甚至是你想的东西。
you from the things you hear, even the things you think.
一个党卫军。
A Waffen SS man.
今天训练的时候他过来找我们。
He came to speak to us in training today.
他告诉我，我的技艺很好。
He told me my skills are superior.
他想进一步和我谈谈。
He wishes to speak with me further.
他叫什么名字？
What was his name?
莱贝尔。
Leiber.
排长。
Section leader.
告诉我，莱贝尔打算什么时候和我谈？
Tell me when does Leiber plan to speak to me?
我不觉得他们会要求你打仗。
I don't think they're asking you to fight.
那你有没有问他们为什么不在前线
And are you asking them why they are not out there
亲自上阵，而是在这个地方招募你
fighting themselves these men who walk around recruiting you
这种傻瓜？
idiots?
你为什么要生气？
Why are you angry?
当没有人攻击你的时侯，你很容易击中目标，
It's easy to hit the target when no one is attacking you,
卢茨。
Lutz.
你觉得到东边战场上有时间给你练习？
You think there's time for practice out there in the east?
在那里敌人是真实的，他唯一的目标就是你。
Out there the enemy is real and his only target is you.
这对我来说不是个游戏。
This isn't a game to me.
我很努力训练。
I am training hard.
谁都能看出来。
Everyone can see it.
上一场战争我打了四年的仗，我回来时
I fought in the last war for four years, and when I got
德国比我走的时候还要糟糕。
back Germany was even worse than when I left.
没有工作。
No work.
负债累累。
Debt.
饥荒遍地。
Hunger.
跟你似的，我们心甘情愿地向死亡奔去。
Like you, we ran willingly towards our death.
为了保护我们的家园。
Towards protecting the-- the Homeland.
我们像傻子一样，没有问过一个问题。
Like fools, we didn't ask a single question.
然后这些跟我一起吃饭的同伴，
And all those men, comrades that I ate with,
一起睡觉，一起上厕所的同伴，他们死得毫无价值。
slept with, pissed with-- they died for nothing.
你懂吗？毫无价值！
Do you understand me? For nothing!
我们被羞辱了，被欺骗了。
We were humiliated, cheated.
但是这场战争，这场战争是我们的。
But this war, this war is ours.
你不能做出任何改变。
You cannot make a difference.
不是那样的。
That's not true.
广播：德国
ANNOUNCER : Germany will
将从奸诈的盖世太保和谋杀犯党卫军中解放，
be freed from the Gestapo hyenas, the SS murderers,
任何相信希特勒的污秽，
and anyone who believes in the filth of Hitler,
相信民族社会主义
of National Socialism--
和这令人作呕的社会体系。
--and this repulsive system.
我们都会看着它覆灭，不是你的消亡，
We will see the end-- not of you,
也不是德国，因为这场战争不是针对德国人民的。
not of Germany, for the fight is not against the German people.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
相反，英国为了
On the contrary, Britain fights to--
我
I--
让你们从恐怖的
--relieve
you from the monstrous
独裁者中的手中解放而战
hands of a dictator--
妈妈，我只是需要呼吸新鲜空气。
Mother, I just need some fresh air.
他们说服你，他们会
--who convinced you he would
解放德国，但反而
free Germany, and instead--
蕾娜。
Leyna.
他们毁灭了德国。
--has broken it.
她是个黑鬼。
She's a negro.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
蕾娜？
Leyna?
那是你的名字吧？
That's your name?
你为什么过来？
Why did you come?
你可能会惹上很大的麻烦。
You could get into a lot of trouble.
希特勒万岁！
Heil Hitler!
我想看看而已。
I wanted to see what it's like.
希特勒万岁！
Heil Hitler!
看看他在这里干什么。
See what he does here.
科恩。
Koen.
他是我弟弟。
He's my brother.
我知道。
I know.
我见过他和你在一起。
I have seen him with you.
你是在偷窥我们吗？
Were you spying on us?
只有一次。
Only once.
他是德国人。
He's German.
当然。
Of course.
我见过一位长得像你一样的女士。
I've seen a lady that looks like you.
在一张照片里。
In a photograph.
好吧，其实不是一张照片。
Well not really a photograph.
我的父亲，他有一台留声机。
My father, he has a gramophone.
他把他的爵士乐唱片都藏起来了，但我听他偷偷放过。
He hides jazz records, but I've heard them playing quietly.
有时侯，深夜里，我在我房间的时候，
Sometimes, late at night, when I'm in my room,
如果我把耳朵贴在地板上，我就能听见。
if I press my ear to the floor, I hear.
黑人音乐。
Negermusik.
那不正是这种音乐的名字吗？
Isn't that what it's called?
它们是被禁止的。
It's not allowed.
我们要是在友好的环境下，
When we're in a friendly situation,
我的话语也许听起来不这么悦耳。
my conversation might not be smart.
但如果我们能彼此理解，
But if we're to have a perfect understanding,
我们就叫它将心比心吧。
let's call a heart a heart.
在一本杂志的封面上有一位女士。
On the cover of one of the magazines there's a lady.
她和你一样。
She's like you.
有点美丽。
Kind of beautiful.
你唱那些歌会惹上麻烦的。
You'll get into trouble singing those songs.
我只需要小心一点就行了。
I'll just have to be careful.
像我父亲一样。
Like my father.
来吧。
Come on.
你有没有上去过那里？
Have you ever been up there?
那些山丘上？
Into those hills?
那是世界上最安静的地方。
It's the quietest place on earth.
我之前经常上去收集毛毛虫，
I used to go up there to collect caterpillars,
跟我父亲和母亲一起
with my father and my mother.
你在那里可以看到整个柏林。
You can see all of Berlin from that one place.
你离家出走了吗？
Did you run away?
离家出走？
Run away?
因为你的母亲，她是
It's just your mother, she is--
她不是犹太人。
She's not Jewish.
不，我知道，但是
No, I know, but--
你的父亲
your father.
他…他是个黑人。
He-- He's a negro.
你有没有在晚上游泳？
Have you ever swam in the night?
就是黑到什么也看不见的时候。
You know, when it's so dark you can see nothing.
我一直在想那会是多么美妙。
I always thought it would be so wonderful.
那你为什么没这么做过？
Then why have you never done it?
在鲁德谢姆，我每周都游泳。
In Rudesheim I'd swim every week.
那里有很多犹太人。
There were many Jews.
他们不能用游泳池。
They were told they couldn't use the pool.
然后，他们说我也不能用。
And then-- I was told I couldn't use it either.
很久之前的事了。
It's been a long time, that's all.
我有过自己被水淹死的噩梦。
I have dreams that I'm drowning.
你只需要再适应水就行了。
You just have to get used to the water again.
你可以和我一起跳进来。
You can jump in with me.
接下来
Now the next--
希特勒万岁。
Heil Hitler.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
蕾娜！
Leyna!
蕾娜？
Leyna?
蕾娜！
Leyna!
蕾娜。
Leyna.
我来。
Here.
接下来你不能瞎走了。
This bit you need to know where you're going.
我真不敢相信我把我的自行车借给你了。
I can't believe I lent you my bike.
我母亲为我们做的。
My mother had them made for us.
我和父亲。
For me and father.
她也有一个吗？
Does she have one too?
她去世了。
She's dead.
哦，我
Oh, I--
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
这就是你来这里的原因吗？
Is that why you come here?
来思念她？
To think of her?
有时侯是。
Sometimes.
更多时候，我都在想打仗是什么感觉。
Mostly I think of what would it would be like to fight.
为德国而战，像我父亲一样。
To stand up for Germany, like my father did.
你觉得你能杀人吗？
Do you think you could take a life?
杀掉一个活生生的人？
Kill a human being?
我当然可以。
Of course I could.
我可以轻松杀死一名俄罗斯士兵。
I could kill a Russian soldier with ease.
噢，我母亲要觉得我搞事情了。
Ooh, my mother will think I've been up to something.
用我的衣服吧。
Use my jumper.
会方便一点。
It's easier.
你不害怕吗？
Aren't you afraid?
害怕什么？
Of what?
打仗。
Fighting.
战争。
War.
战争让你感到害怕吗？
Does the war frighten you?
是的。
Yes.
我父亲打了仗。
My father fought in the war.
真的？
He did?
为了德国？
For Germany?
当然。
Of course.
BBC广播员：这里是英格兰。
BBC PRESENTER : Here is England.
这里是英国。
Here is England.
这里是BBC午夜新闻。
Here is the BBC midnight news.
同盟国现已进军至欧洲大陆的国家。
The Allies' advance into mainland Europe continues.
英国精英部队和美国军队 -
British Elite Forces, along with US troops--
我父亲是为德国而战的吗？
Did my father fight for Germany?
你再说一遍？
Beg your pardon?
今天拿下了
--have today captured
法国的瑟堡港 -
the French port of Cherbourg--
他是法国军人。
He fought for the French.
一名塞内加尔士兵。
A Tirailleur Senegalais.
在西部前线。
--from the western front.
胜利包括
The victory included--
你是告诉过我他是被派到这边来打仗的。
You told me he was sent here to fight.
你没告诉我他是来打我们的！
You didn't tell me he was sent here to fight us!
这是他的语言！
It's his language!
我们见面时，他已经是部队的成员了。
He was part of the Occupation by the time we met.
他不是你的敌人。
He didn't fight you.
也不是我的。
Or me.
他当然是。
Of course he did.
我是德国人，即便你想装作你不是。
I am German, even if you want to pretend you are not.
即使你想让我装作我不是。
Even if you want me to pretend I'm not.
我爱过他。
I loved him.
正是爱才让你降临在这个世界上。
It was from that place that you came.
科恩甚至都不是。
A place even Koen cannot claim.
是你再次让我成为众矢之的。
You have made me an enemy twice.
如果你觉得我让你变成了敌人，
If you think I've made you the enemy,
蕾娜，那你看看你周围吧！
Leyna, then look around you!
听着，蕾娜。
Look, Leyna.
下次你再和那个纳粹的儿子在一起的时候，
And the next time you are with that son of a Nazi,
你要知道
you know this--
如果他父亲发现你和他儿子在一起，他会杀了他。
If his father catches you with his boy, he'll kill him.
然后来杀掉我们！
Before he comes and kills us!
我忘带手套了。
I've forgotten my gloves.
我等你。
I'll wait.
不，你继续走吧。
No, you go on.
我一会儿就好。
I'll be just a moment.
这是你的选择，蕾娜。
It's your choice, Leyna.
你一直在这里。
You're always here.
在工厂外面。
Outside the factory.
你冷吗？
Are you cold?
不。
No.
你呢？
Are you?
嗯，这是最冷的夏天。
Yes, it's the coldest summer.
我把手套丢了。
I've lost my gloves.
我跟我母亲说我落下了。
I told my mother I left them.
我得走了。
I have to go.
我不想让我母亲再对我失望了。
I don't want my mother to be more upset with me.
我想给你个东西。
I wanted to give you something.
奶酪。
Cheese.
也许你可以跟科恩和你母亲一起享用它。
Maybe you could enjoy it with Koen and your mother.
我以为你走了
I thought you had gone.
蕾娜，我母亲没有等我。
My mother didn't wait for me, Leyna.
在那之后我就怀上你了
And that's just how I became your mother,
追逐和你面前一样的不可能。
chasing the same impossibility you are chasing.
你父亲第一次看到我时，
The first time your father looked at me,
我认为这世上除了他不会再有人
I thought my heart would never beat again
让我有活着的感觉。
unless he loved me forever.
然而这之后他从我身边被别人带走了，蕾娜。
He was ripped away from me, Leyna.
我剩下的只有你了。
And all I had left was you.
世上最好的事物。
The best of everything.
你觉得我能离开你吗？
So you think I could ever leave you?
我们两个都有依靠。
For each of us there is someone.
对我来说是你，蕾娜。
For me it's you, Leyna.
你父亲留给我的礼物。
The gift from your father.
科恩是我的心脏，你知道的。
Koen is my heart, you know that.
但对我来说，那个依靠是你。
But for me, that someone is you.
塞巴斯蒂安：一个肮脏的英国人。
An unwashed Englishman.
一个法国狒狒，从头到脚都是黑的。
A French baboon, black from head to toe.
黑得像你的姐。
Black like your sister.
如同蕾娜一样，黑得像煤。
Black as coal like Leyna.
站好队！
HITLER YOUTH COMMANDER: Get in line!
动起来！
Move!
习惯了，是吗？
Used to it, aren't you?
嘴里含着肮脏的土？
Dirt in your mouth?
一个好的士兵应该有尊严。
A good soldier should have honor.
科恩！
Koen!
科恩，你还好吗？
Are you all right, Koen?
科恩！
Koen!
什么？
What?
你还爱我吗？
Do you still love me?
不。
No.
我恨你。
I hate you.
你是个女孩，我讨厌女孩！
You're a girl and I hate girls!
我没有
I have not
这些不是老文件！
These are not old papers!
别拿那些拿走！
Don't take those!
你要带我去哪儿？
Where are you taking me?
你们这里有犹太人吗？
You have Jews here?
只有我们三个。
It's just the three of us.
我儿子在卧室里睡着了。
My son is asleep, in the bedroom.
她的文件呢？
Where are her papers?
去拿来，蕾娜。
Go fetch them, Leyna.
没事的，科恩。
It's all right, Koen.
他们很快就走了。
They'll go soon.
盖世太保士兵：出生于鲁德谢姆。
Born in Rudesheim.
德国人。
German.
你是个黑鬼，但你说你是德国人。
You are a Negro, but you say you are German.
我们会去弄新的来。
We will have them replaced.
你不用再去找那个党卫军莱贝尔了。
You, er, won't be reporting to SS Leiber.
他觉得你在别的地方会更有用处。
He thinks you'll be of more use elsewhere.
打仗？
Fighting?
我们需要我们能找到的每一个人。
We need every man we can get.
哦，所以你知道我们的人都要
Oh, so you do realize that our men are freezing to death
在俄罗斯前线冻死了？
on the Russian front?
他们带着荣耀牺牲。
They are dying with honor.
不是没有意义的。
It's not for nothing.
不，这只是个盲目的妄想。
No, it's for blind delusion.
你说完了吗？
Are we finished?
我能走了吗？
May I go now?
卢茨，等等。
Lutz, wait.
你母亲为了活命用她身躯的每一部分战斗。
Your mother fought for her life with every part of her being.
她不会想看到你随随便便牺牲的。
She wouldn't want to see you throw away yours.
你必须戴上能帮助你避免战争，
You wear the mask that gets you through the war,
帮你活命的面具。
that helps you survive.
你要是不爱德国，如果你没准备好牺牲性命
Why did you fight for Germany if you don't love it?
那你为什么要替国家打仗？
If you weren't prepared to die.
卢茨，别随便给我戴帽子。
Don't judge me, Lutz.
你跟我当时一样。
You are just as I was.
我能为了德国死上10多次。
I would have died for Germany 10 times over.
别人那时候做出了这样的牺牲。
Others made that sacrifice then.
他们现在也会如此。
And they will make it now.
就让他们去吧。
Let them.
卢茨，我首先是你的父亲。
Lutz, I am your father first of all.
你懂我的意思吗？
Do you understand?
不，我不懂。
No, I don't.
你想让我理解你的感受，但你不愿意
You want me to feel as you feel, but you don't want
我像你一样出战。
me to fight like you fought.
你想让我有独立的想法，
You want me to have an independent mind,
但如果跟你的相背，你就不乐意了。
but not if it goes against yours.
我应该是谁？
Who should I be?
我应该成为你，还是不？
Should I be you or not?
你不是个英雄。
You are not a hero.
我也不是。
And neither am I.
我们今天不能去山顶了。
We can't go to the hilltop today.
我得想办法回家。
I have to try to get back home.
你应该等等
You should wait.
哪里都是他们的人。
They'll be everywhere.
等？
Wait?
把这个戴上。
Put this on.
戴上，快点！
Come on, quick!
蕾娜！
Leyna!
我们要去哪？
Where are we going?
一个安全的地方。
Somewhere safe.
等到事情都平息了。
Until things calm down.
我父亲，他昨天去慕尼黑了。
My father, he left for Munich yesterday.
坐下。
Sit down.
你饿吗？
Are you hungry?
不，谢谢。
No, thanks.
渴吗？
Thirsty?
我也不。
Me neither.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
谢什么？
What for?
你做我的朋友
Being my friend.
我想喝点水。
I will have some water.
你妈妈，她看起来很善良。
Your mother, she looked kind.
你一定很想她。
You must miss her terribly.
我父亲，他之前经常为她落泪。
My father, he used to cry a lot.
那是最可怕的。
That was the worst.
我只有一张我父亲的照片。
I only have one photograph of my father.
我想给你看点东西。
I want to show you something.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我告诉你了。
I told you.
这是他最常放的。
This one he likes to play most often.
比利假日酒店，“让我们开心吧。”
我们要是在友好的环境下，
When we're in a friendly situation, my
我的话语也许听起来不这么悦耳。
conversation may not be smart.
但如果我们能彼此理解，
But if we're to have a perfect understanding,
我们就叫它将心比心吧。
let's call a heart a heart.
她去世后，每当我听到这个音乐
After she died I would hear this music
我就会告诉自己，我要是使足够劲
and I would tell myself if I looked hard
往门缝里看
enough through the crack in the door
我就能看到她在这里，和我父亲一起跳舞。
I would catch her in here, dancing with my father.
如果我告诉你我梦中的需求，
If I tell you what my dreams have been demanding,
我们就叫它将心比心吧。
let's call a heart a heart.
我们可以跳舞。
We can dance.
我能用一句话
Can I prove how I yearn
来表达我的渴望吗？
just by the turn of a phrase?
当我的灵魂燃烧时，我还能控制自己吗？
Can I keep my control when all my soul is aflame?
也许你会称某人为真正的
Maybe you would call a true
confession and indiscretion
忏悔和轻率。
on someone's part.
但如果我要说我多么疯狂地崇拜你，让我们称之为一颗心
But if I'm to say how madly I adore you, let's call a heart--
嘘。
Shh.
是詹恩，做家具的
It's Jann, the furniture maker.
没关系，他看不见你。
It's all right, he can't see you.
他几乎是个瞎子。
He's almost blind.
只能看见形状，如果你离得非常近他也许也会看到。
Its only shapes, or if you're really close.
他想干什么？
What do you think he wants?
我父亲给他提供工作。
My father gives him work.
他大概是把一些工具落在后面了。
He probably left some tools in the back.
他走了。
He's leaving.
柏林现在应该清除干净了。
Berlin is supposed to be clear by now.
我想这就是今天有这么多行动的原因了。
I think that's why there's so many actions today.
你不用害怕。
You don't have to be scared.
“清除干净？”
"Clear?"
没有犹太人了。
Of all Jews.
我听到我父亲走之前说的。
I heard my father talking before he left.
去年为了元首的生日，
For the Fuhrer's birthday last year,
柏林得清空犹太人。
Berlin was to be clear of Jews.
但犹太人和德国人结婚了，那些混血的犹太人，
But the Jews married to Germans and the half Jews,
他们还在。
they still remain.
他们把这些“清除”到哪里？
Where do they "clear" them to?
应该是波兰。
Poland, I think.
那里的劳动营。
Camps for labor.
与其让他们坐在那计划推翻我们
Better they work for Germany than sitting here plotting
还不如让他们给我们干活。
and planning against us.
这不简单，你知道吗。
It's hard, you know.
盖世太保来找犹太人，但是找到了我。
The Gestapo come looking for a Jew and they find me.
不会持续太久的。
Not for long.
不会一直这样的。
It can't stay like this forever.
德国总会平静下来。
Germany will be calm again.
会没事的。
It will be all right.
你觉得美国是什么样的？
What do you think America is like?
为什么问？
Why?
你给我看的那个杂志上的女人
That woman you showed me on the magazine--
她是美国人。
she's American.
所以呢？
So?
你觉得她快乐吗？
Do you think she's happy?
他们在美国会吊死像你这样的人，蕾娜。
They hang people like you in America, Leyna.
他们在集会上给我们看书。
They show us in books at meetings.
人被吊在树上，被烧死。
People hanging in trees, set on fire.
你做过那样的事吗？
Did you ever do that before?
什么事？
Do what?
我们刚做的事。
What we just did.
当然。
Of course.
什么时候？
When?
第一次是什么时候？
When was the first time?
我不知道。
I don't know.
几年前。
A few years ago.
几年前？
A few years?
别说话，蕾娜。
Be quiet, Leyna.
你想你从来没有过像抚摸我一样
I don't think that you ever touched anyone the way
抚摸过任何人
that you just touched me.
来，把这个穿上。
Here, put this on.
现在是什么时候？
What time is it?
9点以后了。
It's after 9:00.
什么？
What?
卢茨，宵禁。
Lutz, the curfew.
停下！
Halt!
希特勒万岁。
Heil Hitler.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我…我从特雷普托拿点书。
I'm-- I'm collecting some books from Treptow.
我要准备明天的一个集会。
I'm preparing for a meeting tomorrow.
你不能在白天做？
And you couldn't do it in daylight?
就在晚上晃来晃去？
Just skulking around in the dark?
鲁茨：我刚从训练回来。
I just returned from training exercise.
你住在哪？
Where do you live?
嘿!
Hey!
科佩尼克。
Koppenick.
我住在科佩尼克。
I live in Koppenick.
威斯穆勒的儿子？
Weissmuller's boy?
走吧，快走，待会儿你就得被抓了。
Go on, get on your way,
before you get arrested.
蕾娜！
Leyna!
我等你进去了。
I'll wait until you get inside.
卢茨。
Lutz.
我们今天做的
What we did today--
你以前做过吗？
did you ever do that before?
没有。
No.
从今天开始
From here on, you will not leave
我要是不跟着你，不要离开屋子
the house unless I'm with you.
你证明了你不能被信任。
You've shown you can't be trusted.
你可能被逮捕的。
You could have been arrested.
我不是犹太人。
I'm not Jewish.
不是。
No.
但你也不是雅利安人，蕾娜。
And nor are you Aryan, Leyna.
我们最后都得为你的错误负责。
We'll all have to pay for your mistakes in the end.
我，你，甚至是科恩。
Me, you, even Koen.
我们都得负责。
We'll all have to pay.
你只会指责我的错误
You speak of nothing but mistakes,
那你自己犯过的错呢？
but who's paying for yours?
这正是为什么我不会看着你把你的生命抛在一边。
And that's why I will not watch you throw your life away.
你不能再接近那个男孩了。
You will not go near that boy again.
我道歉。
I apologize.
不好意思。
Excuse me.
你！
You!
停下。
Stop.
停下！
Halt!
现在！
Now!
停下，蕾娜。
Stop, Leyna.
我们必须停下。
We have to stop.
待在这。
Stay here.
你们两个！
Both of you!
妈妈，我没有绝育的文件。
Mother, I have no sterilization papers.
没有身份证件。
No identity papers.
我会解释。
I will explain.
这是你的杂种？
Your bastard?
我的女儿。
My daughter.
你的黑鬼杂种。
Your Negro bastard.
你在工厂工作？
You're at the factory?
文件呢？
Papers?
是。
Yes.
快点。
Quickly.
是。
Yes.
这里。
Here.
她的文件？
Her papers?
是。
Yes.
告诉我
Tell me--
当你羞辱德国的时侯，你心里在想什么？
What was in your heart when you were shaming Germany?
我从来没有羞辱德国。
I have never shamed Germany.
她的文件！
Her papers!
你是德国的耻辱。
You are Germany's disgrace.
你和你的杂种。
You and your bastard.
闭上你的嘴。
Close your mouth.
黑人的妓女。
Black man's whore.
你迷失了。
You're lost.
忘了做一个优秀德国女人是什么感觉。
Forgotten what it is to be a good German woman.
你觉得你迷失了吗？
Do you think you are lost?
我没有。
I am not lost.
也许确实不必永远迷失。
Perhaps not forever.
那么告诉我，你要怎样成为一个优秀的德国女人？
So then, how do you become a good German woman?
你要扔掉你的猴子。
You lose your monkey.
妈妈。
Mama.
什么？
What?
我们把她带走或者把你带走。
We take her or we take you.
- 不不不！ - 蕾娜：妈妈！
- No, no, no!   - Mama!
求你了！求你了！
Please! Please!
求你了，我求求你！
Please, I beg you!
不，求求你！
No, please!
求求你！
Please!
求求你，带走我吧！
Please, take me!
闭嘴！
Be quiet!
把我带走！
Take me!
不！
No!
妈妈！
Mama!
不！
No!
你不许哭。
You don't cry.
你不能哭。
You do not cry.
妈妈。
Mama.
妈妈！
Mama!
她为什么没告诉我？
Why didn't she tell me?
她连再见都没说。
She didn't even say goodbye.
她让我替她说再见。
She told me to say goodbye for her.
这份工作会给她丰厚的薪水，而且我们不必等太久。
This work, it will pay her good money and it won't be for long.
多久？
How long?
我不知道。
I don't know.
但她爱我们。
But she loves us.
你不会离开你爱的人太久的。
And you can't be away from people you love for very long.
所以现在，我知道，就在此刻，
So I know, right now, right this minute,
她在尽可能努力回来。
she's working as hard as she can to get back to us.
我可以和她一起去的。
I could have gone with her.
不，你不能。
No, you couldn't.
打扰一下，先生？
Excuse me, Herr?
我是恩格尔先生。
Herr Engel.
我刚要去找卢茨和他父亲。
I was going to visit Lutz and his father.
我不确定他是不是还在慕尼黑。
I wasn't sure if he was still in Munich.
他回来了。
He's back.
哦。
Oh.
卢茨你已经错过了。
Lutz you missed already.
他被召去履行义务了。
He was summoned to duty.
一天前。
One day ago.
义务？
Duty?
本来以为还有一个月时间
Thought he had one month but they came for him
但他们昨天一大早就找到他了。
early yesterday morning.
把他送去东边了。
Sent him to the east.
没有提前预警。
No warning.
他到时侯了。
It was his time.
希望我的时候还能再来。
Wish it was mine again.
柏林除了女人和老男人，什么也没有。
Nothing in Berlin except women and old men.
哼。
Huh.
还有藏起来的犹太人。
And hiding Jews.
你之前说一个人不能离开
Is it true you can't be away from people
爱的人太久，是真的吗？
you love for very long?
当然是。
Of course it is.
科恩？
Koen?
过来。
Come.
文件。
Papers.
身份证明。
Identity papers.
发生什么了？
What's happening?
我想他们要把我们搬到发动机工厂。
I think they're moving us to the engine factory.
文件。
Papers.
是什么？
What is it?
发生什么了？
What's happening?
他们在找什么？
Who are they looking for?
把她带走
Take her away.
文件。
Papers.
他们在查每个人的文件。
They're checking everyone's papers.
看，看！
Look, look!
一个女的跑走了！
A woman is running away!
抓住她！
Get her!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
快点。
Quickly.
进去。
Get in.
闭嘴。
Shut up.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
下一个。
Next.
快点。
Hurry up.
过来。
Come here.
你是个混血？
You're a mischling?
是。
Yes.
我母亲是雅利安人。
My mother is Aryan.
绝育了？
Sterilized?
是。
Yes.
我在鲁德谢姆绝育了
I was sterilized in Rudesheim--
莱茵兰。
The Rhineland.
你母亲没有帮到你什么忙。
Your mother did you no favors.
是她让你变成了一个黑鬼。
She rendered you a Neger.
别以为她的纯种有多了不起
Don't cling to her purity because she
以为她没把你也变成纯种。
didn't care to make you pure.
吉普赛？
Gypsy?
你是个法国人？
You a Partisan?
不。
No.
我爱德国。
I love Germany.
但他们把我母亲和我的文件带走了。
But they took my mother and my papers.
他们说祖国没有黑人这种东西。
They say there is no such thing as a Negro of the Fatherland.
那你怎么看？
And what do you say?
我觉得
I say--
我觉得我是德国人。
I say I am German.
站到这里。
Stand here.
我会给你做
I am going to do for you
你母亲不能给你做的事。
what your mother couldn't.
我会给你一次活下去的机会，
I am going to give you a chance for life,
因为毕竟不是你玷染了德国种族。
because it was not you who defiled the German race.
你只是恶心的结果罢了。
You are merely the sickening produce.
你会在厨房工作。
You will work in the kitchen.
你吃我们你给的饭一点也不能多。
You will eat the food you are given and no more.
如果你试着占小便宜，你会提前死
If you take advantage, you will die before your time,
就像你母亲本应那样。
as your mother should have.
你在我的床铺上。
You are in my bunk.
哦，闭嘴，黑鬼。
Oh, hush, Negro.
你觉得你比我高一等？
You think you are better than me?
你省口劲儿吧。
Spare your energy.
你不在那边的老鼠房里已经很幸运了
You are only lucky you are not in the rat house over there
像个...
like--
你觉得我是犹太人？
You think I am Jewish?
我只想在我妹妹旁边睡。
All I want is to sleep near my sister.
但像你这样的非洲野蛮人不会懂的。
But an African savage like you wouldn't understand.
你为了活命能吃掉你母亲。
You would eat your own mother to keep alive.
只有傻瓜睡在那底下
Only a fool sleeps down there where they piss and empty
别人都往你头上拉撒。
themselves on you from above.
行吧，你可以睡我的床铺。
Well you can sleep in my bunk.
睡在这里的那些女孩呢？
Where are the girls that sleep here?
去医务室了。
Infirmary.
他们回不来了。
They won't be back.
那些鞋会给你惹麻烦的。
Those shoes will cause you trouble.
我知道，但它们很结实。
I know but they are strong.
那下面伤寒肆虐。
Down there is ripe for typhus.
我受够了被排挤了。
I'm tired of being pushed out.
你肚子是圆的。
Your stomach is round.
我在洗澡间里看见过。
I've seen it in the wash barracks.
你知道那里面发生些什么事儿吗？
Do you know what happens in there?
哪里？
Where?
犹太老鼠房。
The Jewish rat house.
这空气我呼吸不了。
I can't breathe with this air.
我怎样才能证明我的向往
How can I prove how I yearn
只是一个短语的转折？
just by the turn of a phrase?
当我所有的灵魂都燃烧起来时，我能保持控制吗？
Can I keep control when all my soul is aflame?
但如果我要说我多么疯狂地崇拜你，
But if I'm to say how madly I adore you,
让我们称呼一颗心。
let's call a heart a heart.
给，拿我的吧。
Here, take mine.
拿着。
Take it.
我在厨房里吃过了。
I ate in the kitchen.
赫敏，你的脚要烂了。
Your feet are rotting, Hermine.
要是可以，我给你带一个土豆。
When I can, I'll bring you a potato.
你可以用它来买鞋。
You can use it to buy shoes.
好吗？
OK?
昨天晚上，我吃了冰淇淋。
Last night, I ate ice cream.
甜甜的香草冰淇淋。
Sweet vanilla ice cream.
我在我母亲的怀抱里睡着了。
I was asleep in my mother's arms.
我闻到了她皮肤的味道。
I smelt her skin.
我感受到了她的心跳。
I felt her heart beat.
他们带走了她而不是我。
They took her instead of me.
我永远不会原谅自己。
I will never forgive myself.
我说我已经绝育了。
I have said that I am sterilized.
赫敏，疼。
Hermine, it hurts.
你会习惯它的。
You will get used to it.
站住！
Halt!
你从哪来，要到哪去？
Where are you coming from and where are you going?
先生，我从厨房来要回到我的营房。
Sir, I'm returning from kitchen duty to my barracks.
你从厨房拿了食物。
You carry food from the kitchen.
交出来。
Hand it over.
先生。
Sir.
把你的衣服脱掉。
Take off your clothes.
赶紧！
Hurry up!
快点。
Come on.
你想被打死吗？
Do you want to be shot?
把你的衣服脱掉。
Take off your clothes.
现在。
Now.
喂!
Hey!
她做了什么？
What has she done?
黑人杂种。
Negermischling.
你之前见过吗？
You seen one before?
从厨房偷东西。
Thieving from the kitchen.
看她哆嗦的。
See how she shakes.
她在藏食物。
She's hiding food.
我想处置她。
I should like to deal with her.
她…她太卑鄙了。
She-- She is miserable.
让我带走她
Let me take her.
我想搜她的营房。
I want to search her barracks.
继续吧。
Go ahead.
如果你受得了这黑人的恶臭。
If you can stand the Neger's stench.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
等等。
Wait.
停下！
Stop!
你睡哪里？
Where do you sleep?
我们得走。
We have to walk.
你的住所在哪？
Where is your block?
我们睡在同一个营房。
We sleep in the same barracks.
她能和我回去吗？
Can she return with me?
你那里有食物吗？
Do you have food in there?
过来。
Come.
你脸色看起来很苍白。
You look pale.
你生病了吗？
Are you sick?
没有。
No.
你离犯人远一点。
You stay away from the prisoners.
集中营泛滥了，我们跟不上了。
Camp is riddled, we can't keep up.
你为什么把我带过来？
Why did you bring me here?
就为了和你待一起吗？
Was it just to be with you?
这很糟糕吗？
Well is that so bad?
现在，犹太人在给别人贿赂食物
Right now, the Jews are bribing each other with food just
只为了离一个自己爱的人近一些
to be close to a loved one.
无论你打仗还是在这里，
Whether you fight or you are here,
你周围尽是死亡。
you are surrounded by death.
但至少在这里没人朝你开枪。
At least here you're not being shot at.
只要你穿着制服
And no one can doubt your loyalty
没人能怀疑你的忠诚。
if you wear the uniform.
“戴上能让你避免战争
"You wear the mask that will get you through the war
让你存活的面具”。
and allow you to survive."
这个煮过了。
It's cooked.
能帮你弄到一双好鞋。
I will get you good shoes.
到明天之前，我觉得我得帮你保管。
I think I should look after it for you until tomorrow.
来吃一小口。
Have a small bite.
但就一口，不然你得被自己气死。
But just one or you'll be furious with yourself.
他需要一个年轻健壮的人。
He needs someone young and strong.
跟他去
Go with him.
你必须跟我说话。
You have to talk to me.
你怎么到这里的？
How did you get here?
你母亲呢？
What about your mother?
弟弟？
Brother?
那卢茨呢？
What about Lutz?
他怎么了？
What happened to him?
我被叫过来了。
I was called.
我没有时间。
I had no time.
我不知道怎么给你传信。
I didn't know how to get word to you.
我以为他们会派我打仗。
I thought they would send me to fight.
但他们把我送到了个集中营。
Instead they sent me to a camp.
东边。
East.
整天都是皮肤和骨头的味道。
All day the smell of skin and bone.
我受不了。
I can't bear it.
你在那样的地方工作过？
You have worked in a place like that?
没有。
No.
但我见过被选到去那边工作的犹太人。
But I have seen Jews selected to work in them.
去杀人房间。
In the killing rooms.
去杀别的犹太人？
To kill other Jews?
不会有幸存者的。
But there will be none left.
毒气不会停下来的。
The smoke never stops.
不，它不会。
No, it doesn't.
我想让它停下，但我不知道该怎么办。
I want to make it stop but I don't know how.
你为什么盯着我？
Why are you staring at me?
你看起来有变化。
You look changed.
公共厕所。
The latrines.
我晚上会在附近值班。
I'll be on duty nearby tonight.
找我。
Meet me.
我会带食物来。
I'll bring food.
不。
No.
你必须吃东西，蕾娜。
You need to eat, Leyna.
我还没有收到你的命令。
I haven't received the order from you.
什么命令？
Which order?
清除孩子。
Clearing the children.
在指挥官缺席的情况下，
In the absence of the Commandant,
需要你的签名。
it needs your signature.
我还有更要紧的顾虑。
I've had more urgent concerns.
你要是没发现，我们缺了60辆坦克
In case you haven't noticed, we're 60
马上就要输掉战争了。
tanks short of losing the war.
是，我对把感染了的尸体留给美国人
Yes, and I'm not interested in leaving diseased corpses
也不感兴趣。
for the Americans to find.
你呢？
Are you?
你知道为什么你总是这么多传言的起因吗？
Do you know why you were always the cause of so many rumors?
你说不了你到底在想什么
Your inability to say what's going on in your mind
和你对伙伴的选择。
and your choice of company.
总是这么可疑。
Dubious, always.
你的朋友，俾斯麦宰相，
Your friend,
Bismarck Schonhausen,
在柏林被逮捕了
has been arrested in Berlin--
和15个人一起密谋与元首作对。
plotting against the Fuhrer, with 15 others.
他应该像狗一样被绞死。
He should be hanged like a dog.
他的儿子也一样，如果他们还有脑子的话。
So should his son, if they have any sense.
出于父亲的罪过之类的。
Sins of the father and such.
你说他拜访过你家多少次？
How many times would you say he visited your home?
跟你差不多，尤特纳。
About as many times as you, Juttner.
你昨天没来。
You didn't come yesterday.
我给你带了这个。
I brought you this.
和一些食物。
And some food.
先生，这个东西被发现在集中营里，
Sir, this was found in the camp,
和囚犯的首饰一起。
amongst jewelry from the prisoners.
是个威斯穆勒指环，是吧？
It is a Weissmuller ring, isn't it?
谢谢你，彼特。
Thank you, Peter.
你可以走了。
You can go.
我脏死了。
I'm filthy.
让我抱你
Let me hold you.
你为什么那样呼吸？
Why do you breathe like that?
我冷。
I'm cold.
蕾娜？
Leyna?
嗯。
Yes.
我上次抱你是六个月前。
I last held you six months ago.
蕾娜，你怕我吗？
Leyna, you are afraid of me?
有人这样伤害过你吗？
Did someone hurt you this way?
这是我做的吗？
Did we do this together?
跟我一起走。
Walk with me.
这不是战争。
This isn't war.
伤害普通人。
Harming ordinary people.
这不是一个士兵该做的事。
It isn't what a soldier does.
哼。
Hm.
你这么觉得？
You think so?
这正是一个士兵做的事，
That is precisely what a soldier does,
不论他愿不愿意。
whether he wants to or not.
这就是战争。
That is war.
我跟你说过，你的选择决定你的生死。
I told you your choices would keep you alive or see you dead.
你来了这里，所以你活着。
You came here, so you're alive.
那是你的选择。
Those were your options.
选择生存或死亡。
Choose life or choose death.
你跟我说过，我们不是英雄。
You told me we are not heroes.
你应该说的是我们是懦夫。
What you should have said is that we are cowards.
起来。
Up.
起来！
Up!
起床！
Get up!
马上！
Now!
快点！
Come on!
我的鞋呢？
Where are my shoes?
你拿了我的鞋吗？
Did you take my shoes?
你拿了她的鞋吗？
Did you take her shoes?
你拿了我的鞋吗？
Did you take my shoes?
你拿了她的鞋吗？
Did you take her shoes?
我的鞋呢？
Where are my shoes?
- 我的鞋在哪里？ - 赫敏。
- Where are my shoes?   - Hermine.
我的鞋呢？
Where are my shoes?
赫敏，停下！
Hermine, stop it!
她死了！
She's dead!
贝兹，蕾娜。
Betz, Leyna.
你知道他会对我做什么吗？
Do you know what he will do to me?
他是个杀人的猪。
He's a murdering pig.
我看到我的家人去你们叫老鼠房的地方。
I saw my family go to the place you call the rat house.
在那里，他们一个一个消失了。
Where, one by one they disappeared.
我母亲，她跟我说永远不要承认自己是个犹太人。
My mother, she told me never admit you are a Jew.
那就是活着的方法。
That is how to stay alive.
蕾娜，我还活着。
I'm alive, Leyna.
我错过了毒气来这里劳作。
I missed the smoke and came here for labor.
赫敏。
Hermine.
现在，因为我没有鞋，我要死了。
And now, I will die because I have no shoes.
你不会死。
You will not die.
没有鞋？
Shoeless?
为什么？
Why?
先生，我的鞋昨天晚上在营房里被拿走了。
Sir, my shoes were taken in the barracks during the night.
威斯穆勒。
Weissmuller.
跟着我
Join me, will you?
打死她。
Shoot her.
你笑了？
Do you laugh?
你觉得她的厚颜无耻很有趣？
You find her insolence amusing?
是吗？
Do you?
嗯？
Eh?
你应该杀了她。
You should have killed her.
这样我就可能会理解你是谁了。
Then I might understand who you are.
她没有武器。
She had no weapon.
那不是我想作战的方式。
That's not how I wanted to fight.
她是个犹太女孩。
She was a Jewess.
她告诉我了。
She told me.
德国告诉我们全世界都在跟我们作对，
Germany told us the world is against us,
但我只看见德国在杀自己的国人。
and yet all I see is Germany killing its own people.
蕾娜，我们要去
Leyna, we need to go somewhere where
别人永远不会认识我们的地方。
nobody would ever know us.
离开德国，离开
Away from Germany, away from--
卢茨，你看我的时侯，你看见的是什么？
Lutz, when you look at me, what do you see?
我不是吉普赛人。
I am not a gypsy.
我不是犹太人。
I'm not a Jew.
即使在这个集中营，他们也告诉我没有属于我的地方。
Even in this camp they tell me I have no place to belong.
我看见一个德国女孩，对自己的祖国敬爱忠诚。
I see a German girl, loyal and dutiful to the Fatherland.
但我从来都不被允许爱它。
But I was never allowed to love it.
你不应该爱我。
You are not supposed to love me.
但我爱。
But I do.
赫敏死了，被迫否认她的身份。
Hermine died, forced to deny who she was.
而我现在得替我们两个活下去，
And now I must live for both of us,
每天都宣告我是谁。
declaring every day who I am.
这里，在我自己的国家里。
Here, in my country.
他们会杀掉你和我们的孩子。
They will kill you and our child.
如果孩子能活过这一切，
If the baby has survived all of this,
我也可以。他们不想让我有孩子。
then so can I. They didn't want me to have a child.
但她和我会成为一切的证据
But she and I will be
the evidence of all
她和我是他们想要否认的一切
that she and I are and all that they try to deny--
我是个德国黑人。
that I am a German Negro.
在我们都有所归属的地方爱我吧，卢茨。
Love me where we both belong, Lutz.
我们至少得离开这里。
We have to at least get out of here.
躲在什么地方，等到战争结束。
Hide somewhere until the war is over.
我可以偷辆汽车，自行车，什么都行。
I can steak a car or bike, anything.
我们…我们不能待在这里。
We-- we can't stay in this.
求你了。
Please.
我们逃跑的话，不会活着出去的。
We will never make it out alive if we try to escape.
你救不了我。
You can't save me.
你能救我吗？
Can you save me?
我想让你好好呼吸，每天早上晚上都吃上饭
I want you to breathe properly, and to eat morning and night
不用怕在这个地方会被杀掉
without the fear that you will be murdered in this place
没有人告诉我，我要成为一个杀人犯。
that-- that tells me that I should be a murderer.
我不想让你再害怕了。
I don't want you to be afraid anymore.
很快会结束的。
It will be over soon.
对于我们大家来说，是真正的结束。
For all of us it will be over.
犯人一旦被转移，我会为你做安排
Once the prisoners are moved, I'll make arrangements for you
回到柏林。
to go back to Berlin.
转移？
Moved?
怎么转移？
How?
铁道被炸了，路被毁了
The railway lines are bombed, the roads destroyed
很危险。
and dangerous.
他们走路。
They'll walk.
我们转移他们。
We'll move them.
一点一点的...
Little by little.
他们会死的。
They'll die.
大部分人自己上厕所都很困难。
Most of them can barely make it to relieve themselves.
或者你现在想走？
Or perhaps you want to go now?
不。
No.
我不走，现在还不。
I'm not going, not yet.
他们从两边一块冲我们来。
They're coming at us from both sides.
我不知道谁会先到这里，但我保护不了你。
I don't know who will reach here first but I can't protect you.
我不想让你保护我。
I don't want you to protect me.
那这个呢？
And this?
你想让我把这个放回犯人的营房里？
You want me to put it back in the prisoners' barracks?
别让我为你选择。
Don't make me choose for you.
蕾娜。
Leyna.
这件事你要快点做。
You will have to do this quickly.
他们几天后会转移集中营。
They will start moving the camp in days.
我有一套给你的制服。
I have a uniform for you.
我不能走出大门。
I can't walk through the gates.
我不行！
I can't!
我们坐一辆摩托车。
We will use a motorcycle.
我会找到一辆。
I will get one.
我保证
I promise
卢茨，我们会死的。
Lutz, we will die.
蕾娜，我们会拥有新的生活。
Leyna, we will have a life.
新的生命。
A life.
快点！
Come on!
轰炸越来越近了！
The bombing is getting closer!
我不行！
I can't!
他们要把我们带到哪里？
Where are they taking us?
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we going?
发生什么了，盖堡？
What's happening, Kapo?
我不知道。
I don't know.
走！
Go!
抓紧！
Hurry up!
女营发生什么了？
The women's camp, what's happening?
你已经在转移他们了。
You're moving them already.
我们不得不这么做。
We have to.
你和我今天离开。
You and me leave today.
你本来打算什么时候才告诉我？
And when were you going to tell me?
我现在就在告诉你。
I'm telling you now.
我不走！
I won't go!
那就只剩你和小偷还有犹太人一起。
Then it will be you, the thieves, and the Jews.
你活下来的几率有多大？
How do you rate your chances?
你了解你自己吗，卢茨？
Do you know yourself, Lutz?
了解吗？
Do you?
是，我了解我自己。
Yes, I know myself.
还有你！
And you!
你知道她对我来说意味着什么。
You know what she means to me.
如果你把她带走，我会死的。
And if you take her away, you will kill me.
你觉得和一个黑鬼给未来做打算
And you think planning a future with a Negro
能让你活着？
will keep you alive?
我不会让你因为她被逮捕，被折磨。
I refuse to let you be arrested and tortured because of her.
德国不会让你活着。
Germany will not let you survive.
你不会活下来的！
You will not survive!
父亲，她怀了我们的孩子。
Father, she is having our child.
我们必须活下去！
We have to survive!
我们必须。
We have to.
他们会把你吊死。
They will hang you.
一个
A
先生，我们得走了。
Sir, we have to go.
没时间了。
There is no time.
蕾娜！
Leyna!
卢茨！
Lutz!
我在这！
I'm here!
蕾娜！
Leyna!
卢茨！
Lutz!
蕾娜！
Leyna!
卢茨！
Lutz!
蕾娜！
Leyna!
拜托，我在尽力帮助你们所有人。
Please, I'm going to try to help all of you.
请报上您要找的亲人的
Please have the full name, age, and occupation of the relative
全名，年龄和职业。
you are searching for.
如果你知道你的亲人所在的上一个集中营
If you know the last camp your relative was taken to, please
把这个信息也准备好。
have this information ready.
你好。
Hi.
蕾娜・施莱格尔。
Leyna Schlegel.
啊。
Ah.
我在找我的阿姨。
I'm looking for my aunt.
你能帮我吗？
Can you help me?
我在找我的兄弟。
I'm looking for my brother.
我在找我的家人。
I'm searching for my family.
我在找我的姐姐。
I'm looking for my sister.
关于她最后的消息是1943年在弗洛森比格集中营。
She was last known in
Flossenburg Camp in 1943.
她最后一次在集中营里被看见
She was last
seen in Camp
如果你知道你的亲人上一个集中营
If you
know the last camp
准备好这个信息。
your relative was taken to,
please have this information.
我可以提供给你已知的所有关于
You'll ask me for all last
known information on the person
你要找的人的最后消息。
you're searching for.
请将咨询对象信息准备好。
Please have this ready.
不好意思。
Excuse me.
我找我的女儿。
I'm looking
for my daughter.
妈妈！
Mama!
看！
Look!
蕾娜！
Conceal!